瓦雷利亚末日
伊耿一世（AC1-37 在位）
“征服者”
镶嵌红宝石的瓦雷利亚钢王冠
坦格利安家族征服维斯特洛
雷妮丝
伊耿一世的妹妹和妻子
伊尼斯一世（AC37-42 在位）
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
杰赫里斯一世（AC48-103 在位）
“和解者”“人瑞王”
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
杰赫里斯一世（AC48-103 在位）
“和解者”“人瑞王”
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
亚莉珊（AC36-100）
“善良王后”
杰赫里斯一世的妹妹和妻子
贝尔隆（AC57-101）
“勇敢的”“春晓王子”
杰赫里斯一世的儿子和国王之手
阿莱莎（AC60-84）
贝尔隆的妹妹和妻子
戴蒙
“浪荡王子”
贝尔隆的儿子 韦赛里斯一世的弟弟
科利斯·瓦列利安
“海蛇”“潮汛之主”
雷妮丝
“无冕女王”
韦赛里斯一世的堂姐
兰娜尔·瓦列利安（AC100- ）
科利斯和雷妮丝的女儿
奥托·海塔尔
韦赛里斯一世的国王之手
韦赛里斯一世（AC103开始在位至今）
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托的女儿 韦赛里斯一世的第二任妻子
韦赛里斯一世（AC103开始在位至今）
镶嵌翡翠和珍珠的黄金王冠
爱玛·艾林（AC82-112）
韦赛里斯一世的表妹和第一任妻子
奥托·海塔尔
韦赛里斯一世的国王之手
阿莉森·海塔尔
奥托的女儿 韦赛里斯一世的第二任妻子
雷妮拉
韦赛里斯一世的女儿和王储
改编自 《血与火：坦格利安王朝史》
[美] 乔治·马丁 著
龙 王 家 族
第一季 第四集
狭海之王 King of the Narrow Sea
黑港城的城墙……
...the wall Blackhaven
由玄武岩筑成 高不可攀
are unscalable basalt stone.
城堡四周由一条干涸的深沟环绕
And the castle is surrounded by a deep, dry moat.
即使未来多恩入侵 城堡也绝对坚不可破
It is well fortified against any future Dornish incursions.
虽然我的宝座略小
And though my seat may be lesser in size,
但城堡位置优越
it is situated most pleasingly.
克里斯顿·科尔
御林铁卫 雷妮拉·坦格利安的护卫
雷妮拉·坦格利安
龙石岛公主 王储
博蒙德·拜拉席恩
风息堡公爵
我和父亲曾有幸接待过亚莉珊王后
The view across the Marches is inspiring,
当时她说 边疆地的景色十分震撼人心
so said Queen Alysanne herself when she honored my father and I--
告诉我 唐德利恩大人
And tell me, Lord Dondarrion,
您觉得我的曾祖母有世人说得那么美丽吗？
did you think my great-grandmother as beautiful as they say?
公主 那已经是半个世纪前的事了
This was half a century ago, Princess.
是的 的确
Yes, it was.
这话恐怕不太得体 公主
That was unseemly, Princess.
这个人比我的父亲还老
The man is older than my father.
还争着想成为我的夫婿
It's unseemly for him to put himself forward
这才是真的不得体
as a contender for my hand.
下一位！
Next!
又来了个小孩
And now a child.
布莱伍德是一个古老的家族 有着强大的军事力量
The Blackwoods are an ancient house with a formidable army.
他们曾在河间地称王统治
In the Riverlands, they once ruled as kings.
先民之血依旧流淌在他们体内
The blood of the First Men still flows in their veins.
开始吧
Go on.
公主殿下……
My Princess...
自从我祖父的祖父 卢卡斯·布莱伍德
ours is a bond that has long endured,
在征服战争中为龙王效力以来
since Lucas Blackwood, the grandsire of my grandsire,
我们两家的深厚情谊传承已久
aided the Dragon in his war of conquest--
是呀 布莱伍德家族真是在战场上扭转乾坤了呢
Aye, the Blackwoods truly turned the tide on that one.
我们历史悠久 融合了先民血脉
Coursed with the blood of the First Men,
深深扎根在这片土地上
our history is deeply rooted in this land,
正是您的家族令我们能在此安居乐业
which your house has made its home.
公主 如果我被选为您的夫婿……
If chosen as your match, Princess...
您的生活将会无比轻松
your days shall be easy
我也将保护您日夜周全
and nights safe under my protection.
“保护”？公主可是有一条龙的 你这蠢货
"Protection"? The Princess has a dragon, you dumb cunt.
布雷肯！
Bracken!
这小子我倒是有点喜欢
I could learn to like that one.
让我们有请下一位吧
Let us have the next
赶快结束就能去吃晚饭了
so we may go to supper.
懦夫
Craven.
我们走吧
We're leaving.
布雷肯家族与布莱伍德家族自安达尔人入侵前便为世仇，
布雷肯家族在安达尔人入侵后改信七神，而布莱伍德家族有着坚定的旧神信仰。
把剑收起来 你们这群蠢材！
Sheathe that steel, you twats!
通知码头 让奥斯温船长把船准备好
Send word to the harbor and have Captain Oswin ready the ship.
公主 我们应该在三天后再去苦桥的
Princess, we're due in Bitterbridge in three days' time.
只要能结束这荒唐的选夫大会
I would happily row myself back to King's Landing
我非常乐意自己划船回君临
if it brought an end to this ridiculous pageant.
别看 公主
Don't look, Princess.
公主 我们一小时内就可以登岸了
We should make landfall inside the hour, Princess.
你觉得他会怎么想？
How do you think he will take it?
您是说拒绝陛下派来的所有求亲者
Do you speak of how you rejected every suitor
还是说突然结束这场原本
His Grace put before you, or how you abruptly ended the tour
还剩两个月的巡游呢？
with two months remaining?
隐蔽！
Take cover!
公主！
Princess!
您还好吗？没事吧？
You all right? Are you?
- 快把学士找来！ - 我没事
- Fetch the maester! - I'm fine.
科拉克休
戴蒙的龙
韦赛里斯·坦格利安一世
国王
此剑为“黑火”，是坦格利安家族祖传宝剑之一，
曾为“征服者”伊耿的佩剑。有人认为这把剑象征着王权。
是戴蒙
It's Daemon.
奥托·海塔尔
国王之手
哈罗德·维斯特林
御林铁卫队长
戴蒙·坦格利安
“浪荡王子” 韦赛里斯的弟弟
把它加到王座里吧
Add it to the chair.
你戴了一顶王冠
You wear a crown.
你自立为王了吗？
Do you also call yourself "King"?
我们战胜三城同盟会后
Once we smashed the Triarchy,
他们称我为“狭海之王”
they named me "King of the Narrow Sea."
但我明白 陛下您才是唯一真正的国王
But I know that there is only one true king, Your Grace.
我的王冠以及石阶列岛……都属于您
My crown and the Stepstones... are yours.
科利斯大人在哪里？
Where is Lord Corlys?
他驾船回潮头岛了
He sailed home to Driftmark.
- 那是谁在据守石阶列岛呢？ - 潮水……
- Who holds the Stepstones? - The tides...
螃蟹 以及两千死去的三城同盟会海盗
the crabs, and 2,000 dead Triarchy corsairs,
我将他们曝尸沙滩 以儆效尤
staked to the sand to warn those who might follow.
起来吧
Rise.
王国欠你一笔大大的封赏 弟弟
The realm owes you a great debt, brother.
来吧
Come.
这是我们的好机会……
This is our chance...
戴蒙 他会外出探险 海外游历
Daemon, he would venture off, abroad,
赢下比武大会……
winning tournaments...
不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
我不会再争论这个话题了
I will not revisit this debate.
你一直都是母亲的最爱
You were always mother's favorite.
不 这不是什么了不起的大秘密
No, it's no great mystery.
你一直是她的最爱
You were.
我们的母亲 她才不管什么习俗 传统或是规矩
Our mother, she had no regard for custom or tradition, rules.
可惜啊 我并不是什么武艺高超的勇士
And I, sadly, was no great warrior.
恭喜您大获全胜
Congratulations on your victory.
谢谢您 公主
Thank you, Princess.
阿莉森·海塔尔
王后 奥托之女
或许戴蒙王子想去长廊转转吗？
Perhaps Prince Daemon would care for a tour of the gallery?
他还没有见过诺佛斯和科霍尔
He hasn't yet seen the new tapestries
给您送来的新挂毯呢
gifted to you by Norvos and Qohor.
你想去看看新挂毯吗？
Would you like to see the tapestries?
他对这些东西才不感兴趣
He has no interest in such things.
我挺想去看看
I'd like to see them.
那你不用拦着自己
Then you should not deprive yourself.
那我自己去欣赏了
I shall enjoy them alone.
倒酒
More wine.
我说了 你才是母亲的最爱
As I said, you were the favorite.
不 你是 你才是 我坚信
No, you were. You were. I insist.
我猜巡游不怎么顺利
I surmise the tour did not go well.
我已经尽力忍了很久了
I endured it for as long as I could.
七国上下每一个年轻的骑士和贵族都来讨好你……
To have every young knight and lord in the Seven Kingdoms fawning over you...
这可真惨啊
What misery.
对于全国女孩来说 能在两个提亲者当中选择就很难得了
It is rare for girls in this realm to get a choice between two suitors,
更不用说有四十个能挑的
no less two score of them.
那些男人和男孩并不是想讨好我
Those men and boys don't fawn over me.
他们只是奔着我的名号和瓦雷利亚血统来的
They only want my name and my Valyrian blood for their offspring.
我倒觉得还挺浪漫的
I think it's rather romantic.
关在城堡里 被逼着生出子嗣
How romantic it must be to get imprisoned in a castle
还真挺浪漫
and made to squeeze out heirs.
对不起
Sorry.
他有多生气？
How angry is he?
陛下花了很大心思为你安排这次巡游
The King went through great effort to arrange your tour.
他很……沮丧
He is... frustrated.
不过你回家了 我很高兴
But I am glad you are home.
我发现自己现在已经没什么朋友了
I find I have few friends lately.
我多希望现在我还是阿莉森小姐 不过……
I like to believe I'm still the Lady Alicent, but...
在所有人眼里 我都只是“王后陛下”
all anyone sees when they look at me now is "The Queen."
我也想你了
I've missed you, too.
你看上去在龙石岛过得很满足
Hae hunē kirine Zaldrīzdōrot īlō vestretas.
为什么要回来呢？
Skoro syt āmastā?
你回来肯定不只是为了戏弄我父亲
Sīlāvose umbun aōho āmāzinot kepe ñuhe mīvindigon toliot ilzi.
所以……
So...
你想要什么？
what do you want?
只想回归家庭温暖
Only the comforts of home.
我以为你在这个家里感受不到什么温暖
I had not thought you particularly comfortable in this home.
不过我觉得 这次冒险之后你好像变了
Though I do suppose you seem changed by your adventures.
或许 变得更成熟了
More mature, perhaps.
你这四年也成熟了许多 公主
You've matured yourself these last four years, Princess.
你会习惯众人瞩目的
You'll get used to the attention.
受人关注我可以忍受
The attention I can endure.
忍不了是别的事
It's the rest I could do without.
我父亲似乎很想把我卖给拥有最大城堡的领主
My father seems content to sell me off
不管是谁 只要城堡够大他就满足了
to whichever lord has the biggest castle.
你不知道可能还有更糟糕的交易呢
There are worse things to be sold for.
婚姻不过是一场政治上的安排
Idīnnon dēmalio syt verdilla mērī issa.
结了婚以后 你可以想干什么就干什么
Dīnakson toliot, gaoso gaomagon kostas.
对男人来说 婚姻或许是政治上的安排
Valo syt, idīnnon dēmalio syt verdilla sagon kostus.
对女人 婚姻就像宣判死刑
Ābro syt, vējītsos.
如果是这样的话 我早就摆脱我那个青铜婊子了
Hegnīr iksos jaelan. Nyke hen ñuho Brāedāzmo Bratsiot ēlio ono gō dāerēdoks.
你的妻子很幸运
Ābrazȳrys aōhys biare istas;
你没有让她怀孕
ziry lēdetō daor.
我都怀疑 那么恶劣的环境里 孩子能不能长大
Keso qrinuntenko tolālȳti ūbriljagon rūs nājumban.
我的母亲被逼诞下子嗣 直到这件事最后害死了她
Muña ñuha dārannī āpykagon isētaks vapār ziry morghākotas.
我不会让自己也遭受同样的命运
Hēnkos vējose botilun daor.
发生在你母亲身上的事是一场悲剧
Aōhe muñe imassitas līr mundāzma istas,
但这世界本就充满悲剧
yn kesy mundāzmo vȳs issa.
你不能一生都活在恐惧中 那样你会错过人生最精彩的部分
Glaeson aōhon zūgose glaesagon kostō daor, iā jāhī albijossa āzālilē.
我不想活在恐惧中
Zūgose glaesilun jaelon daor.
只想独自生活
Mērpāvose glaesilun.
听起来多么孤独啊
Such a lonely prospect.
赢回石阶列岛本该归还王国所有
The Stepstones were meant to be won for the realm,
但这么多天过去了 我们似乎只是
but over the past few days, it seems we have traded
把螃蟹喂食者换成了海蛇
a crabfeeder for a seasnake.
他明显是在报复您迎娶阿莉森王后 拒绝兰娜尔小姐
This is clearly a rebuke for passing over Lady Laena for Queen Alicent.
他为女儿求亲那件事 已经过去了好几年
Years have passed since the business with his daughter.
他不会还在耿耿于怀吧？
Certainly, he cannot still be wroth?
毫无疑问  “海蛇”过于自负 陛下
The Sea Snake is an over-proud man, to be sure, Your Grace.
梅罗斯
大学士
林曼·毕斯柏里
财政大臣
莱昂诺·斯壮
法务大臣
之前的请求被拒 有损他的自尊心
That pride has been injured.
或许我们可以设法弥合伤口？
Perhaps we can salve the wound?
恐怕科利斯大人的自尊是眼下最不需要操心的事
I fear Lord Corlys's pride is the least of our worries.
无意给您带来更多困扰 陛下
I don't wish to cause you further distress,
但我哥哥从旧镇送来一条令人不安的消息
Your Grace, but my brother has sent disturbing word from Oldtown.
据称 科利斯伯爵正在密谋
Lord Corlys is said to have engaged in negotiations
与布拉佛斯海王商谈婚事
with the Sealord of Braavos.
他打算把女儿兰娜尔嫁给海王之子
He plans to wed his daughter Laena to the Sealord's son.
如果瓦列利安家族与
If House Velaryon entered into an alliance
自由贸易城邦结盟
with the Free Cities
那么
then...
泰兰·兰尼斯特
海政大臣
我们也应当善用我方资源缔结婚约
we would have to seek our own marriage pact.
- 晚安 克里斯顿爵士 - 祝您好梦 公主
-Good night, Ser Criston. -Sleep well, Princess.
穿上这个
Kesommi aōle mīsās.
推开挂毯后面的墙
Rhakiāzmo inkot dōros indīs.
沿着通道走
Geltilio rȳ jās.
我在外面等你
Ninkiot avy rhaeninna.
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we going?
滚开 小子
Fuck off, boy.
他管我叫“小子”
He called me boy.
你想知道自己的死法吗？孩子
Do you wish to know your death, child?
让我来吧
Let me take that.
全都退下
Leave us, all of you.
你的动作比她们轻柔多了
You have a far kinder touch than they do.
谢谢 我的夫君
Thank you, husband.
现在来说说伟大的铁王座
And now we come to the matter of the great Iron Chair...
以及谁的屁股会坐上去
and whose bum it might bear.
我们的好国王
Our good King...
选定了他的女儿
names his daughter,
一个女孩 作为继承人
a girl, his heir.
但后来 他又有了一个孩子
But then to him, a babe is born.
是个儿子！
A son!
谁会继承铁王座？
To which heir might the chair bear?
会是谁？
Who will it be?
是弟弟？还是女儿？
The brother? The daughter?
还是三岁的小王子？
Or the little princeling of three?
雷妮拉 王国之光
Rhaenyra... the Realm's Delight,
一个女孩 如此年轻 势单力薄
a girl so young and so slight...
她被所有臣民爱戴
loved by all of her people,
但她能成为强大的女王吗？
but would she make a powerful queen,
- 还是弱不禁风？- 弱不禁风！
-or would she be feeble? -Feeble!
还有伊耿 小王子 没准他也盯着王位
Though Aegon, the babe Prince, might long for a claim,
他有两样东西 雷妮拉不能比
he has two things Rhaenyra cannot:
他有征服者的名字
a conqueror's name...
还带着把儿
and a cock.
谎言 诽谤！嘘！
Lies, slander! Boo!
就当是笑话吧
Jest if you will,
不过这些市井小民更愿意相信
but many of the smallfolk are like to believe
作为男性 伊耿应当成为继承人
that, as a male, Aegon should be the heir.
随便他们怎么想 不重要
Their wants are of no consequence.
如果你日后想要统治这群人 他们怎么想就很重要
They're of great consequence if you expect to rule them one day.
一个晚上就好 我想卸下继承人的重担
For one night, I wish to be free of the burdens of my inheritance.
四个铜板 臭老鼠
Four coppers, street rat.
在君临城 我们为自己的欢愉买单
In King's Landing, we pay for our pleasures.
- 喂！- 站住！小子！
-Hey! -Stop! Boy!
你等着 我会抓到他
Wait, I'll find him.
你跑什么 在躲谁？
And who might you be running from, now?
哈尔温爵士
Ser Harwin.
哈尔温·斯壮
“碎骨人” 莱昂诺的长子
公主
Princess.
请别
Don't.
注意点 小子
You take care, boy.
下次你可就没这么幸运了
Next time, you might not be so lucky.
挺开心的 对吧？
Enjoyed that, did you?
谁知道下次品尝自由的味道 要等到什么时候
Who knows when I'll next taste freedom?
进来
Come.
请您原谅 王后陛下
Pardon me, Your Grace.
国王陛下请您过去
The King has requested your presence.
现在很晚了
The hour is quite late.
是的 王后陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是人们满足需求的地方
It's where people come to take what they want.
你看 性爱也是一种欢愉
Fucking is a pleasure, you see.
男女都一样
For the woman as it is the man.
婚姻是责任 没错
A marriage is a duty... Yes.
但婚姻并不会阻止我们追求快乐
But that doesn't stop us from doing what we want.
睡我们想睡的人
From fucking who we want.
戴蒙？
Daemon?
公主？
Princess?
公主 您 您受伤了吗？
Princess, are you, are you hurt?
- 我该通知御林铁卫队长 - 别
-I should alert the Lord Commander. -No.
我的头盔
My helmet.
您闹够了吗？
You finished?
谢谢
Thank you.
请停下
Stop.
很抱歉在深夜打扰您 大人
Apologies for the late hour, my Lord.
什么事？
What is it?
白蛆托人给您带个话
A messenger brings word from the White Worm.
梅莎丽亚
“白蛆”“小梅夫人” 戴蒙的情妇
你把我当成犯人了吗？
Am I your prisoner?
就像你曾经对我那样？
As I was once yours?
你很幸运 我是你的保护者
I'm your protector, lucky for you.
喝了这个 可以解酒
This will cut the fog.
我不需要一个普通的妓女来保护我
I don't need protection from a common whore.
我并不普通
I am not so common.
好吧 一个并不普通的妓女
A not-so-common whore then.
我早已告别了那种生活
I've left that life behind.
皮肉交易能给予我的非常有限
I learned that skin-trade could only take me so far in this life.
你向来不安分
You never were one to stay idle.
我并不想历经磨难 但也只能咬牙忍受
Hard lessons are not welcomed but suffered.
出门时记得去付房钱
You can pay for the room on your way out.
进来
Come.
什么事？
What is it?
陛下 万分抱歉 一大早就打扰您
I apologize for the early hour, Your Grace.
我有
I have...
有些让人不安的消息
discomforting news.
我想 最好在御前会议召开前 先私下向您禀告
I thought it best shared discreetly before the council convenes.
是海蛇吗
The Sea Snake.
陛下 恐怕此事和公主有关
I'm afraid it concerns the Princess, my King.
她受到伤害了？
Has she been harmed?
把女儿的一些事情告知父亲
It is no easy thing
并非易事
to tell a father of his daughter's exploits.
我也想保持沉默 但是——
I had considered saying nothing, but--
她做了什么？
What has she done?
昨晚 有人见到公主
The Princess was spied last evening...
在红堡外的
beyond the walls of the Keep...
一所妓院里
in a pleasure house.
你说什么？
What of it?
她和她的叔叔搞在一起
She was carrying on with her uncle.
他们的所作所为 有损公主的
They were engaged in behaviors unbecoming of a maiden...
贞洁之名
of a Princess.
什么所作所为
What behaviors?
我必须明说吗 陛下
Well, must I say it, Your Grace?
你走进我的寝宫 指责我的女儿 又不把话说清
You enter my bedchamber, accusing my daughter of something.
你直接点吧
Now speak it... plainly.
有人看见戴蒙和雷妮拉在一起
Daemon and Rhaenyra were seen together...
在妓院深处
in the bowels of a pleasure den.
他睡了她
Coupling.
胡说八道
This is a lie.
你被骗了
You have been lied to.
我也希望是这样 陛下
I only wish that were true, Your Grace.
是谁在传播谣言？
Who is responsible for this gossip?
立刻把这个造谣的带来见我
Have this rumormonger brought before me at once.
我要挖掉他的眼睛
And I will take their eyes.
作为首相 收集可靠情报是我职责所在
As your Hand, I must maintain trusted sources of information.
这次的眼线非常可靠 至今从未失手
And this one, as yet, has never led me astray.
并且 好几个仆人已经承认
And several of the servants have now admitted to seeing her,
见到公主……
the Princess...
在猫头鹰时
creeping through the gates from King's Landing,
乔装成侍从
disguised as a page
偷偷溜过君临城门
during the hour of the owl.
你被野心冲昏了头脑是吧
Are you so sick with ambition
居然派人跟踪我女儿？
that you would have my daughter stalked?
秘密监视她？
Spied upon?
就等着绝佳机会 好毁掉她的名誉是吧？
Awaiting your best chance to destroy her reputation?
我绝无此意 陛下
I have no such intent, Your Grace.
你自以为很聪明
You think yourself a cunning man.
你那些心思也太明显了吧
Your designs are obvious.
你就那么想把你的血脉推上铁王座
Do you wish to have your blood on the Iron Throne so badly
甚至不惜毁掉我的血脉？
that you are willing to destroy mine own?
出去
Just get out.
立刻给我出去
Leave me... at once.
陛下 告退
Your Grace.
我穿好衣服了 阿诺拉 进来吧
I'm dressed, Annora. Come.
公主
Princess.
过来
Come.
公主 王后让我过来传个话
Princess, I have a message from the Queen.
昨晚发生了什么？
What happened last night?
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我父亲对你提出了一些令人担忧的指控
My father has made some worrying allegations about you.
你当时是和你叔叔在一起吗？
Were you with your uncle?
哦 我……
Oh, I...
我好几年没见过他了
I haven't seen him in years.
他带我到城里去放松一下
He took me into the city for some fun.
全都告诉我 雷妮拉
Tell me the whole of it, Rhaenyra.
你父亲指控我做了什么
Your father accused me of something.
喝酒吗？
That I drank wine?
还是天黑以后离开城堡？
Left the castle after dark?
你在妓院睡了戴蒙
That you fucked Daemon in a pleasure house.
这真是个卑鄙的指控
This is a vile accusation.
是吗？
Is it?
你们坦格利安确实有一些奇怪的传统
You Targaryens do have queer customs.
- 而且戴蒙显然毫无底线 - 阿莉森
-And Daemon certainly knows no limit. -Alicent...
王后陛下 姐姐 你一定要相信我
Your Grace, sister, you must know I would,
我绝不会
I would never.
你不能这样轻信谣言
You cannot believe such gossip.
我父亲所说不是谣言
My father is no gossip.
很显然他被误导了
Well, certainly he's been misled.
这种事他不可能亲眼目睹
He could not have witnessed such a thing.
- 为什么？ - 因为这事纯属捏造
-Why not? -Because it did not happen.
- 有人告诉他——  - 有人？
-He was told that you-- -Told?
谁对你父亲说的这些？
Who made these claims to your father?
我是公主
I am the Princess.
质疑我的品德就是叛国行为
To question my virtue is an act of treason.
- 我并不知道具体—— - 你父亲没有告诉你吗？
-I do not know specifically-- -Your father did not tell you?
他向国王报告此事
He reported it to the King.
我听到了
I overheard.
所以你用无意听到的诽谤……
So you are accusing me of slanders...
来指责我？
you overheard?
我只想帮助你 雷妮拉
I only want to help you, Rhaenyra.
我们去了一家酒馆喝酒
We drank in a tavern.
几家……酒馆
Several... taverns.
后来太晚了……
It was getting late...
我要回家
and I asked to go home.
但戴蒙还想继续
But Daemon wished to continue.
我是跟着他出去的 决定权不在我
As he was my escort, I had no real choice.
“继续”……
"Continue"...
在妓院吗？
in a brothel?
他带我去看了一场表演
He took me to a show.
我只是观看 什么都没做
I was only a spectator. I didn't do anything.
然后戴蒙喝得烂醉
And then Daemon sank into his cups and
就丢下我去找妓女了
abandoned me for some whore.
我早该知道的
I should've known better.
所以你并没有？
So you did not?
真的需要我正式否认吗？
Must I truly refute that?
戴蒙没有碰过我
Daemon never touched me.
我以我母亲的名义发誓
I swear this to you upon the memory of my mother.
把自己置于这样清白会受到质疑的境地
It was foolish of you to place yourself in a position
你真是太蠢了
where your virtue could even come into question.
陛下竭尽全力为你寻找良配
The King has strived to find you a good match.
我也一样
And so have I.
如果那位大人认为你被……
If that lord were to think that you had been...
玷污了……
sullied...
- 那一切都毁了 - 我知道……
-it would ruin everything. -I know...
陛下
Your Grace.
我很后悔
I regret it.
国王命你觐见 王子殿下
The King demands an audience, my Prince.
把你的脏手拿开
Take your fucking hands off me.
我女儿
My daughter.
你都不否认一下吗？
Won't you even deny it?
我得先知道罪名 才能知道要否认什么
I need to understand the charge before I can attempt to discredit it.
你玷污了她
You defiled her.
你还是什么都不说
Still, you say nothing.
有什么关系呢 哥哥？
What does it matter, brother?
我们在雷妮拉这个年龄的时候
When we were Rhaenyra's age,
可是把丝绸街的那些妓院
we fucked our way through most of the brothels
一路干了个遍
on the Street of Silk.
我们是年轻男人
We were young men.
而她只是个小女孩
She is just a girl.
- 你的侄女！ - 雷妮拉是个成年女子了
-Your niece! -Rhaenyra's a woman-grown.
比起我们是跟几个婊子 她的第一次跟我还不错吧
Better her first experience be with me than some whore.
你他妈的——
You fucking--
你毁了她！
You have ruined her!
到了这个地步  哪位大人还会娶她？
What lord will wed her now? In this condition?
谁他妈在意什么大人怎么想？
Who gives a fuck what some lord thinks?
你是真龙 你的话就是金科玉律
You are the dragon. Your word is truth and law.
我一辈子都在维护你
I have spent a lifetime defending you.
但你的心比我想的还要黑
But your heart is even blacker than I thought.
我应该废掉她的继承权 就像当初对你一样 一了百了
I should disinherit her as I already did you and be done with it.
把她嫁给我
Wed her to me.
当我献上王冠时 你说我要什么都可以的
When I offered up my crown, you said I could have anything.
我要雷妮拉 我会接受这样的她
I want Rhaenyra. I'll take her as she is,
按我们的家族传统娶了她
and wed her in the tradition of our house.
你已经结婚了
You are already wed.
征服者伊耿也娶了第二位妻子啊
That didn't stop Aegon the Conqueror from taking a second wife.
你不是征服者
You are no conqueror.
你就是……我命中灾星
You are a plague... sent to destroy me.
让我娶雷妮拉为妻
Give me Rhaenyra to take to wife
我们会让龙王家族恢复往日荣光
and we will return the House of the Dragon to its proper glory.
当然了
Of course.
你觊觎的并非我的女儿 是吗？
It's not my daughter you lust for, is it?
而是我的王位
It's my throne.
回谷地去 戴蒙
Go back to the Vale, Daemon,
到你的合法妻子身边去
to your lawful wife.
努力去重建你身上残存的荣誉吧
Strive to restore whatever scrap of honor remains in you.
不去也行 我不在乎
Or don't. Matters not to me.
只要永远别让我再看见你
As long as you are gone from my sight for good.
如你所愿 哥哥
As you wish, brother.
和她谈过了吗
Have you spoken to her?
没有
No.
雷妮拉天性耿直 她不会撒谎
It is not in Rhaenyra's nature to be deceitful.
您的弟弟却未必如此
I cannot say the same for your brother.
你认为他撒谎了？
You believe he lied?
他说过几句纯粹的真话？
How often does he speak the pure truth?
承认这种事情 对他有什么好处？
How does confessing to such things serve him?
可以削弱您的权威
By reducing you.
无论发生了什么 雷妮拉也不清白
Whatever transpired, Rhaenyra is not innocent.
那是因为戴蒙引诱她堕落
Only because Daemon tried to corrupt her.
戴蒙和雷妮拉都流着真龙之血
Daemon and Rhaenyra share the blood of the dragon.
他们反复无常 从不安分
They are restless and chaotic.
她向我发誓她仍是处子之身
She swore to me that she remains a maiden.
我相信她
And I believe her.
这把匕首 曾为征服者伊耿所有
That dagger once belonged to Aegon the Conqueror.
往上可以追溯到伊纳尔
It was Aenar's before that.
“流亡者”伊纳尔·坦格利安，是坦格利安王室的祖先，
曾在末日浩劫降临瓦雷利亚之前率领整个家族迁至龙石岛。
再往前……
And before that...
就说不清了
It is difficult to know.
伊耿去世前 瓦雷利亚最后的火术士
Before Aegon's death, the last of the Valyrian pyromancers
将他的歌藏在刀刃上
hid his song in the steel.
“我的血脉中……”
"From my blood...
“将诞生预言中的王子……“
"come the Prince That Was Promised...
“他的血便是冰与火之歌”
and his will be the Song of Ice and Fire."
我交付给你的责任
The responsibility I have handed to you,
知晓此事的负担
the burden of this knowledge...
远比王位和国王更重要
it is larger than the throne, the king.
远比你和你的欲望
It is larger than you
更重要
and your desires.
如果是杰赫里斯 他会剥夺你的继承权
Jaehaerys would've disinherited you.
就因为一个谎言？
For a lie?
你甚至都没问我 真相到底是什么
You've yet to ask me for the truth of what happened.
真相不重要 雷妮拉
The truth does not matter, Rhaenyra.
世人的看法才重要
Only perception.
你将自己置于危险境地
You have exposed yourself.
如今我们都得承担后果
Now we must both suffer the consequences.
假如生为男子 那我想睡谁就能睡谁
Were I born a man, I could bed whomever I wanted.
我可以生一打私生子女
I could father a dozen bastards,
你朝堂上那些人连眼睛都不会眨一下
and no one in your court would blink an eye.
你说的没错……但谁让你生为女子
You are right... but you were born a woman.
所以你就要剥夺我的头衔 转而立伊耿为嗣
So you'll strip me of my titles and name Aegon in my stead.
我也想这样
I would.
但我的职责 是将王国团结一心 而不是制造更多分裂
But it is mine to hold the realm together, not sow it with further division.
你选择夫婿的自由到此为止
Your courtship is at an end.
接下来 你将会嫁给兰尼诺·瓦列利安爵士
You will wed Ser Laenor Velaryon,
不得有违
and you will do so without protest.
海蛇之子
The son of the Sea Snake.
就这样拿我来治你的政治顽疾
So I can be a remedy for your political headaches.
你就是我的政治顽疾！
You are my political headache!
你嫁给兰尼诺·瓦列利安
Your wedding to Ser Laenor Velaryon
会将王国最有权势的两大家族团结起来
will unite the two most powerful houses in the realm.
一旦我们的巨龙与舰队联合起来
With the combined strength of our shared dragons and naval fleets,
那就无人胆敢发起挑战
no one would dare to stand against us.
龙王家族
The House of the Dragon
将团结一心 延绵至下个世代
will stand as one for a further generation.
那你会怎么处置停在王座上的秃鹫？
And what will you do about the vulture who perches upon your throne?
什么秃鹫？
What vulture?
你的首相
Your Hand.
奥托·海塔尔忠心耿耿地侍奉了两代国王
Otto Hightower has served two kings loyally and faithfully.
他想让伊耿当王储
He wants Aegon to be named heir.
不达目的 他不会罢休
And he will stop at nothing to see it done.
比如 为了毁掉我而监视我
Including spying on me to bring about my ruin.
你口口声声说着征服者的预言
You speak of The Conqueror's vision
说着需要力量 说着团结王国
and the need for strength and unity across the realm.
但如果你最信任的谋臣一心只为个人私利
But how can that be accomplished
你又怎能实现这一切？
with your most trusted adviser so self-interested?
外面请求觐见的每位领主和贵妇
Every lord and lady that calls for an audience with me,
我的御前重臣 乃至历代所有御前重臣
every man on my small council,
人人自利 谁能例外
and all councils past, has been self-interested.
- 这是人的天性 - 我不同意
- It is unavoidable. - I disagree.
我会履行王储的职责 嫁给兰尼诺爵士
I will do my duty as heir and wed Ser Laenor.
但首先 你要履行国王的职责
But you must first do yours as king.
陛下
Your Grace.
五天
Five days.
抱歉 陛下？
I'm sorry, Your Grace?
那是很多年前了
Though it was some time ago.
很多细节……已然消失在记忆中
The details... they fade in memory.
我的父亲曾是一位健壮的战士和驭龙者
My father was a hale and healthy warrior and dragonrider
当时他正值壮年
at the peak of his abilities.
杰赫里斯举办了盛大的王家围猎
Jaehaerys named a great royal hunt
来庆祝他担任首相
to celebrate him being named the Hand of the King.
五天之后 我的父亲死了
Five days later my father lay dead.
就连比武大会都还没开完
Tourneys last longer.
“勇敢的”贝尔隆
Baelon the Brave,
瓦格哈尔的骑士
rider of Vhagar,
铁王座的继承人……
heir to the Iron Throne...
死于肚腹破裂
dead of a burst belly.
诸神自有黑色的智慧
The gods have a dark wit.
那是残酷的一天
It was a grim day.
- 我记得非常清晰 - 是啊……
- I recall it all too well. - Yeah...
对你来说 那可是个好日子
It was a good day for you.
杰赫里斯让你接替贝尔隆做了首相
Jaehaerys named you Hand in Baelon's stead.
我从没这么想过 陛下
That's hardly how I viewed it, Your Grace.
这是责任
It was a duty.
是你侍奉我的祖父度过了最后的时日
You served my grandsire nobly in his final days.
是你教我怎么成为国王
You are the man that taught me how to be King.
陛下过誉
You honor me, Your Grace.
仅仅五天……
Just five days...
你就从杰赫里斯朝中的无名之辈
you went from being another man in Jaehaerys's court,
一跃成为整个王国的二号人物
to the second most powerful man in the realm.
我在想……
I wonder...
选择将个人利益置于国王之上 又费得了你多少时间呢？
how long did it take you to choose yourself over your King?
陛下？
Your Grace?
爱玛之死是我永远无法治愈的伤痛
I will never recover from Aemma's death.
而阿莉森……
But Alicent...
她陪我度过了最悲伤的时候
she took me through the worst of my grief.
但她的陪伴只是一场精心算计
She was a calculated distraction.
我现在才意识到 你算得太精妙了
I only now realize how well-calculated it was.
太荒谬了
That is an absurdity.
王后爱您……
The Queen loves you...
正如您也爱她
as I know you love her.
你的利益不再与王国一致
Your interests no longer align with those of the realm.
你的判断受了太多干扰
Your judgment has been compromised.
一位忠诚的首相
A loyal Hand must tell his king
必然时时忠言逆耳 陛下
a discomforting truth from time to time, Your Grace.
如果没有做到……
If he doesn't...
就是他的失职
he's failed as a servant.
你是一位忠实的仆从 奥托
You were a faithful servant, Otto.
你为国王与王国奉献良多
The crown and the realm
我将永远铭记
both owe you a debt that can never be repaid.
但我无法再信任你的判断
But I can no longer trust your judgment.
进来
Come.
深夜打扰 请您原谅 公主殿下
I hope you can forgive the late hour, Princess.
这是我精心准备的
I took great care in its preparation.
如果调制不当 要么失灵
If not brewed properly, it can either prove ineffective
- 要么会有不良反应……  - 调制不当？
- or else bear unpleasant-- - Brewed properly?
等等 这是什么？
I'm sorry, what is that?
一种茶 公主殿下
A tea, Princess.
是国王给您的
From the King.
月茶，一种用来避孕及堕胎的草药茶。
它会让您避免任何意外的后果
It will rid you of any unwanted consequences.